Trevor McDougald



Austin, Texas



409-739-6071



Graduated from Texas State University

designing and developing large-scale

writing clean, concise, and clear code

extensibility. Seeking to contribute at a

company by utilizing proficiency in

collaboration and communication.

with a BSc in Computer Science in

December 2019. Passionate about

enterprise applications. Prioritize

to improve maintainability and

www mcdougald.info

Skills

Technical

Programming languages: Python, Java, C

McDougald.Engineer@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/trevormcdougald

github.com/trevormcdougald

Client Side: HTML5, XML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, React

Server Side: Node.js, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: SQL, Travis CI, Git, UML, Linux, Bash, Windows 10, Webpack, Intellij

Professional

Database Management | Version Control | Continuous Integration | Agile Methodologies | Test Driven Development | Professional

Documents

Personal

CPR | Emergency Care | Communication | Active Learning | Collaboration | Time Management

Education

About Me

Texas State University

Pursuing B.S. in Computer Science **Minor**: Applied Mathematics 8/2017 - 12/2019 | San Marcos, TX

COURSEWORK 👼

Unix System Programming Internet Software Development Theory of Automata **Operating Systems** Software Engineering Project Intro to Database Systems Software Engineering Intro to Data Mining Object-Oriented Design & Programming Data Structures & Algorithms Computer Architecture Assembly Language Foundations of CS II

Foundations of CS I

Computer Ethics

Memberships & Activites

GNU Linux Users & Enthusiast

Elements of Computer Programming

- .EXE Computer Science Club
- Intro to Competitive Coding Club
- Association for Computing Machinery
- 5th Austin Diversity Hackathon

References

Available upon request

Projects

Blackjack Casino Game

July 2019 - September 2019

Python Sphinx unittest logging pygame Travis CI

A python library and application for emulating a casino blackjack table.

- The game was designed with a variation of the Model-View-Presenter architecture, where the Presenter acted as a supervising controller.
- The Python logging library is used to implement project wide logging.
- The documentation generator Sphinx is used with Google style docstrings to create a reStructuredText markup document.

E-commerce Shopping Website

September 2019 - Current

EJS CSS JavaScript jQuery AJAX Node.js Express Mongoose Bcrypt Webpack

¡Query and Webpack were used on the client side to design and implement an e-commerce website. User functions and store business logic were set up with an MVC architecture on the server side. MongoDB served as the Model, EJS the View, and Express is was the Controller.

Time Series Analysis & Forecasting on Stock Data

January 2019 - May 2019

Jupyter Notebook Seaborn Scikit-learn statsmodels Scipy NumPy pandas Matplotlib

A historical stock quote was used as the initial dataset for a machine learning classification problem. A Random Forest Classifier was trained to predict days a stock's price increases.

Experience

Lifeguard

June 2017 - August 2017 June 2018 - August 2018

Schlitterbahn Water Park - Galveston, Texas

- · Learned to respond effectively and calmly in emergencies.
- Training in CPR and emergency care to ensure safety.
- Remained aware of situational dangers to keep park visitors safe.

Updated: 1/12/2020